Oh, Delphee...
hope someone's seen you.
We are quite
proud of you, Ana.
I know we don't
say that much...
Or ever.
...but we see now
that your... passion?
...for your studies
was all in service of Imperium.
[Ana] A dragon! A real dragon!
[grunting]
[laughing]
Aww.
You sweet thing.
What's her name?
Subject 152-9a,
but some of the lab techs
have taken
to calling her "Sora."
Sora?
The ancient Imperium
word for "orphan"?
Did something happen
to your family, Sora?
What are you doing?
Demonstrating
the possibilities.
[roaring]
[Ana] What?! No!
No, stop!
Waah!
[horn honking]
Unh!
[gasping] My workbench!
If you won't use
your scientific studies
to support Imperium...
And all that we stand for...
Then you'll just have
to find a new interest.
[bicycle bell ringing]
I believed in you!
I thought you were making
Imperium a better place!
For every living thing!
I know you wish I was a
dutiful Imperian, Mom and Dad,
but I'll never be the daughter
you want me to be...
that Empress Beatrix
wants me to be.
[playing the flute]
[rattling]
[screaming]
[stomach rumbling]
Urchin Fruit,
fresh from Merlopia.
Uh-uh.
Don't run a charity here, girl.
No free food.
And no foreign coin.
The Crossroads
is still part of Ninjago.
Hey, this price is triple
what you charged yesterday.
How can you think about money
when people are hungry?
A crisis for some
is an opportunity for others.
[stomach rumbling]
[gasping]
Thief!
Well? Go after
that little pest!
Bah...
Uh, fine, free fruit
to whoever catches her.
[all muttering]
[panting]
[gasping]
Whoa!
Sorry about that.
Hard to see
over all these pies.
[man] I think she went
thattaway!
[she gasps]
Homemade pies. Plenty in stock.
Ooh, all this chasin's
makin' me hungry.
I'll take this one.
Uh, actually, all out of pies.
We're closed.
Come back tomorrow.
I guess I could make myself
a mustard sandwich
when I get home.
I think we're safe.
[stomach grumbling]
[Arin] You can have one
if you want.
I baked them myself.
[eating]
[swallowing]
[laughing]
Thanks for helping me.
Of course.
The Merge brought everyone
together, right?
So I believe together
is the only way to survive it.
My name's Arin.
I'm An--
Uh, you can call me Sora.
Sora?
What are you all doing here?
[Arin] Frak?
[Ras snarling]
Zane, you're...
big.
I guess a lot's changed
since we last saw each other.
Arin, I...
Ras, let him go!
He is with me by choice.
He's lying. Typical villain.
No. It's true...
Ras is my new teacher.
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪
[♪♪♪]
Oh, hello.
Let's see if you work.
[clicking power button]
[music playing in headphones]
[laughing] Nice!
[growling]
[gasping]
[barking]
Unh!
[turning music volume up]
Wahoo!
[music playing in headphones]
[playing the flute]
This Grapple Gun thing
you made me is amazing.
[shooting]
...or it will be
once I get the hang of it.
You'll be a real Samurai
before you know it.
Just like your heroes.
Not samurai, Ninja.
Masters of Spinjitsu. Ya! Ah!
[Sora] Right, Ninja.
Floyd, Kal, Lane, Mister Wu.
No. Lloyd, Kai, Zane...
[Sora laughing]
You're teasing me.
Only 'cause it's really fun.
I mean, you carry that
green mask everywhere you go.
We didn't have anything
like the Ninja where I'm from.
Then how did you
tease your friends?
I didn't have those either.
About time
you had a proper oven.
That campfire
you've been baking with
is a fire hazard.
[Arin] But it gave my pies
their rustic, crispy flavor.
Aah!
You mean burnt?
Let's fire this baby up.
[rattling]
Aah!
Ah! No, my recipes!
I knew this was all a mistake!
[gasping]
[sighing]
Of course the Ninja's masks
would be flame-resistant.
They'd have to be
with Kai around.
Sora, you okay? Sorry I snapped.
Sora?
You heard the boy.
My student will not
abandon his teacher.
Ras must be brainwashing him.
I'm training him.
Like I was training you.
Until I learned
who you really are!
I don't need a reminder
of how evil Ras is.
Nice people don't trap you
for eternity
in the Nether-Space.
[Lloyd] Enough!
Arin, come back with us.
We've been searching
everywhere for you.
Technically, the search
that brought us here
has been focused on finding
the remaining Prismatic Weapon
that is currently
in the possession
of our former ally, Arin.
He's not our former ally.
Do you have a blade
that looks like this?
It's really important
we find it.
Is this what you came for?
Yes, this Returning Blade
is made of Prismatic Steel.
I've had it for years...
an old battle trophy.
They're what the Forbidden
Five have been after.
With the five Prismatic Weapons,
they can release a Chaos Dragon
that would throw the world
into, well, chaos.
-[branch cracking]
-Look out!
Aah!
These two blades
are the last ones the Five need
to free the dragon.
Then I'll be sure to keep it
out of their hands.
Arin, let us go.
Arin, wait!
You won't trick Arin
like you did me, Ras!
Unh!
[impact]
[groaning]
We don't want to fight you.
Obviously. You're outnumbered.
[sighing] Just let me go.
I need Ras.
Uh, Arin...
Oh, come on!
[laughing]
Looks like we got
another stray.
[chuckling]
Sora, come back!
There's hardly any burning!
Have you seen Sora?
She was just here.
I think she went that way.
Ugh!
Uh, thanks.
Can't go back to Imperium,
but what else is out there?
Gotta be somewhere I haven't
made a fool of myself
and alienated
everyone I care about.
[meowing]
Aw, poor thing.
[purring]
You must be lost.
[meowing]
Here, kitty.
Ah!
[Sora] I won't hurt you!
Sora, wait up! I'm sorry!
[meowing]
[Sora] Don't be scared...
[yowling]
[door slamming]
-[sighing]
-[cackling]
Another lonely Other-Realmer.
You were right.
The Crossroads
is a great source
for workers for the mines.
So many lost souls.
[cackling]
[engine starting]
[struggling]
Aah!
Oh...
[gasping]
Hey! Where are you going?
That's my best friend!
[struggling]
Who was that guy?
My new least favorite person.
I'm not losing Arin again.
Come on!
Since when is the World Forest
Ninjago's newest hot spot?
They're here
for the Prismatic Blades.
They'll have to go
through us first.
Get that blade.
[hissing]
Oh, this should be easy.
You're gonna regret
sending your little army away.
Am I?
Release me at once,
or you'll face
an eternity of retribution!
I see him!
Behind you!
Unh!
Aah!
[screeching]
[roaring]
Aah!
[Arin] Let him go!
Haah!
Yaah!
-[grunting]
-[snarling]
Yaah!
Unh!
Aah!
[gasping]
[grunting]
Lloyd, get out of here
with the Blade.
Let us handle him.
Any thoughts on fighting
against Rising Dragon technique?
Yaar!
Huh? Where did he go?
Aah!
Time to blast this guy
back to the Nether-Space.
Yaah!
Uh... is this guy bugs?
Is this guy bugs?!
Yaah! Aw, that's
worse than puppets.
[cackling]
[struggling]
[Nya] There's too many of them.
[klaxon sounding]
Prepare for
a premature landing.
Do you mean "crash"?
Aah!
What good
is a legendary weapon
if I'm not going to use it?
Aah!
Huh?
[gasping]
Thank you.
Aah! Unh!
[struggling]
Yaah!
Aah!
[grunting]
[Nya screaming]
[struggling]
Aah! Hah!
Huh...
[gasping]
[grunting]
That didn't work out
like I hoped.
[blade slicing]
[sighing]
Let me outta here,
you numbskulls!
[sighing]
[Arin panting]
Hold on, Sora!
[panting]
Think Ninja, Arin.
There's more than one way
to catch a villain.
They have speed,
but I know shortcuts.
Coming through!
Sorry, sorry.
Hmm. These Ooze Berries
would be great in a pie.
Huh! Yaah!
Aah!
Here goes nothing.
[brakes screeching]
Ninja...
now!
[Skulkin] These crossroad
roads are so confusing.
[impact]
[landing]
[meowing]
It's okay, I forgive you.
I know what it's like
to be used
and to hurt people
without knowing better.
[yowling and scratching]
Ow! Ugh!
So much for being nice.
Huh!
Sora!
I'm here to save you.
[cat yowling]
[hissing]
Really?
You said
this was all a mistake.
I thought you didn't want
to be friends anymore.
What?! No way!
Friends make mistakes
all the time. That's normal.
You really haven't had
any friends before, have you?
Come on.
I told you, the only way
through this is together.
I said, take a left!
A left! Yaah!
Whaa!
[Sora gasping]
[meowing]
I've never been so glad
to see that green mask.
So, you think
I look like a Ninja?
-Look out!
-Whoa!
Hey! This isn't a bus.
Get back in your cage.
Hold on tight.
You sure
you can work that thing?
I hope so. It was built
by a genius.
[screaming]
[yowling]
[Skulkin shouting]
[roaring]
Aah!
Unh!
Ugh!
Thanks, just what I needed.
Unh!
What took you so long?
I guess I shouldn't expect
to learn gratitude
from you, huh?
Hurry!
[cutting rope]
[crying out]
[rope tightening]
Unh!
Haah!
[panting]
This fool has become
more of an obstacle
than your former Ninja allies.
[Arin] They're not my former...
Get down!
Unh!
[impact]
[blow landing]
[grunting]
[snarling]
Aah!
Whaa...
Arin!
Yaah!
[gasping]
No!
Whaa!
[Sora sniffing]
Ah, those Ooze Berries
smell amazing!
[Arin crying out]
[Sora] This could be
your best pie yet.
You sure you don't miss
the special burnt crust
my campfire made?
[both laughing]
Stronger together, right?
Together forever.
Hold on!
Take my hand!
[Arin] I got you!
-Thanks for saving me.
-I'm sorry.
Come back with us.
It won't be like before.
We can find your parents.
I already found my parents.
They're dead.
[blow landing]
[roaring]
[crying out]
[grunting]
[snarling]
[squawking]
[growling]
They have all the Blades.
Now there is nothing
to stop them
from unleashing
the Chaos Dragon.
[crying out]
[♪♪♪]